Vimalkumar R

Senior Developer

ABOUT ME

Experienced Senior Developer React Js, Next Js with over all 5 years of experience in CRB Innovative Solution Pvt Ltd., and MiceWerkz Pvt Ltd and Foundever. Excellent reputation for resolving problems and improving customer satisfaction.

WORK EXPERIENCE

CRB Innovative Solutions Pvt Ltd

May 2019-June2021

Front-end Developer

Chennai, Tamil Nadu

June2021-June2022

Micewerkz Pvt Ltd or Tripwerkz India Pvt Ltd

React Developer

Old No: 28, New no: 45 4th Floor, North Usman Road T.Nagar Chennai-600017

Sitel India pvt ltd or Foundever.

June 2022-Current

Bus Analyst (React Developer)

Tril Infopark Ltd, 1st floor Block C Hary Tower Ramanjujan IT SEZ,Rajiv Gandhi Salai, Tharamani Chennai-600113

Coded websites using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Typescript, React Js, Redux toolkit, Material Ui, Mantine React, Prime React, RESTful API Project Using function Base Component, Reusable Component.

- Converted graphic designs to usable web images using Adobe Photoshop and Adobe Xd.
- Ran debugging tools such as firebug and Chrome Inspector to eliminate flaws and glitches prior to publishing.
- Collaborate with marketing department to determine organizational need and design pages to meet goals.
- Responsibilities for overall web project management from development to execution and maintenance

EDUCATION

Bachelors, computer science (Bsc)

Completed

Madurai Kamaraj University Theni, Tamil Nadu August 2017

Hindu Higher Sec School

10+2

Completed July 2014 91 + 7904795494 OR 7094229636

Date of Birth: 16.04.1997

smartvimalkumar1997@gmail.com

7E/38 Corporation colony CMR road, Madurai-625009

https://www.linkedin.com/in/vimalkumar-111729213

SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, JavaScript, Typescript, Redux tookit, React, Next Js, Vite Js

TOOLS

VS code, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Xd, Figma, Aws, Netlify, Github, Azure, Jira,

LANGUAGE

English (Speaking, writing) Tamil (Speaking, writing) Telugu (Speaking)

PROJECT

1. CRB Innovative Solutions Pvt Ltd:

Description: Developed and designed various websites using normal web technologies. Specialized in e-commerce and building construction websites.

Responsibilities: Utilized Adobe
Photoshop to analyze and interpret
customer requirements and design layouts
accordingly.
Created and developed websites with a
focus on user experience and visual
appeal.

2. Tripwerkz Ind Pvt Ltd (or) Micewerkz pvt Ltd

Description: Led the development of a user-friendly Traveling website using NextJs with functional components,

Responsibilities: Handled B2C booking websites, effectively managing customer interactions and enhancing the booking experience.

Collaborated with the team to continuously improve the website's performance and user interface.

Ui Library: Mui

CERTIFICATIONS







SECURITY

Frontend Security:

Minimize the use of sensitive data in frontend JavaScript to reduce the risk of data exposure through inspecting.

Use techniques like Content Security Policy (CSP) to prevent unauthorized execution of scripts.

JWT Token Security:

Ensure that JWT tokens are securely generated, signed, and stored. Use strong algorithms and keys to sign JWT tokens. Set a reasonable expiration time for tokens to limit their validity. Consider using token revocation mechanisms if needed.

Protecting Login Credentials::

Never send plain passwords over the network. Use secure mechanisms like HTTPS to encrypt sensitive data during transmission. Avoid storing plaintext passwords on the server. Use strong hashing algorithms (bcrypt) to securely store password hashes.

3. Foundever

Querify Application

Description: Developed a web application using React 18 with functional components and JSX. The application is called Querify and aims to provide users with a seamless querying experience.

Responsibilities: Implemented the User Entry page, allowing users to log in and log out securely through authentication.

Designed and developed the menu with the following sections:

Dashboard Query and Query Library Reckon, Reckon Library, Recko Explorer Coch Find, Coch Insight, Tickets, Chat Bot in customer chat

Ui Library: Mantine, Prime React

Al Chat Assist:

Description: Created a Chat Assist web page using NextJs 13, with functional components and Typescript (tsx), web socket. The project focuses on facilitating smooth customer and agent bot conversations with several features for analysis and convenience.

Features:

Sentiment scale for gauging customer emotions. Intent Analysis for understanding customer queries better.

Hashtags summary view for identifying trends. Category hits for quick topic classification. Integration of Web Socket for real-time automatic reactions to customer messages.

Ui Library: Mantine,

Al Chat Application:

Description: Created a Chat Assist web page using NextJs 13, with functional components and TypeScript (tsx). The application is called Ai Chat Application and aims to provide users with a seamless querying experience.

Responsibilities:

Customers interact with the AI chat application through a message box. They can initiate conversations and ask for assistance. When a customer asks for available applications, the AI Chat bot show Ai result Important Feature Sentiment Scale Positive Percentage, Negative Percentage, Neutral Percentage to show in ui, Important Keywords customer agent talking generate Keywords. Summary AI-generated overall customer interaction summary, Chat Analysis, Knowledge Base Analysis, Overall Insight many feature generate in AI

Access Control and Login:

If the chosen application requires user authentication, the AI chatbot prompts the customer to log in.

The customer provides their login credentials (username and password) through the chat interface.
The AI chatbot can securely pass these credentials to the application's authentication s